hey guys so if you're struggling to
create product visuals that grab
attention and actually drive sales for
your Ecom brand or you find our photo
shoots are too expensive and this video
is exactly for you I'll show you how you
can use mid journey and Photoshop to
create premium eye catching product
visuals like the ones I made over here
that will turn casual scrollers into
paying customers and by the end of this
video you'll have the exact framework
that I use at my own creative agency
dreamers to create scroll stoping
visuals that will elevate your brand
increase conversions and scale your
content production all of the hassle or
cost of professional photoshoo and with
10 plus years of design and branding
experience I've helped many Brands
create visuals that increase engagement
improve Rass and stand up from their
competition now I'll show you how you
can do the exact same for your brand
let's jump in to Jumping straight into
this I just want to talk about why
Brands need to be used on Mid journey in
2025 um so with mid Journey you're able
to create high quality visuals um at a
fraction of a cost of traditional photo
shoots and this could be done in days
and not weeks compared to traditional
photo shoots and this will really allow
your brand to easy scale your content
production um visual content production
in this
case um and this will allow you to scale
your campaigns without having you know
Crea a fatigue and you know with mid
Journey the beauty of it as well is that
you're able to create these very unique
and visual Aesthetics that stand out and
these can be used to improve your
product pages social media posts email
campaigns and then your ad creators
which is you know great now going on to
this why do having high quality visuals
matter for brand um well your visuals
are your Brand's first touch Point um
and your Brand's first impression um and
for Eon Brands this can really make or
break your customer Deion to buy from
you now you only have a split second to
convince your customers take you
seriously and actually give you
attention so having high quality visuals
helps in that and with a lot of you know
increased competition entering the Ecom
space and it becoming a bit more
saturated having eyat visuals is no
longer a nice to have it's actually a
must to have if you're really looking to
compete um in game right now um and yeah
having strong visuals are just a huge
part of a Brand's overall brand strategy
and will really really significantly
impact your success online now here are
a couple reasons as to why you know um
having visuals actually matter so as I
mentioned before you never get a second
impression a second chance of first
impression so once you've kind of like
um shown up to your customers um eyes um
and you have visuals which are you know
poor they're not going to take you after
that so having high quality visuals just
gives you that good first impression
which you need in order to actually take
them down the customer Journey next one
it helps to build trust and credibility
if your customers and potential
customers are seeing that you have
highly quality visuals it means that
you're invested in your brand and you're
invested um I guess in your product
which shows that you actually care about
your customers and they more likely to
trust you you're able to communicate
emotions without words you know people
say a photo is worth a thousand words
and that you know that's definitely true
when it comes to the case of visuals for
Ecom you know if you're able to have
high quality visuals that communicate a
specific emotion you want customers to
feel about your brand you know it's
going to help you a lot when it comes to
trying to convince customers to purchase
from you it also helps to you know
increase clicks and engagement um you
know having scroll stopping eye catching
visuals using it on your ads will have
your customers become quite curious
about your brand interested to learn
more which means that you're going to
get more you're able you're going to be
able to acquire more customers
um um well you're going to get people to
click on your ads more which means
you're going to be able to acquire
customers um a lot cheaper and also yeah
it allows you to stand out for your
competitors you know if you have visuals
that are different and unique and aren't
you know the same as your competitors
people are going to just pay attention
to you more and it will allow you to
stand out even if your product you know
is the same or even worse than your
competitors you know it just gives you
that edge and overall this just leads to
higher conversion rate
now what makes a visual higher
converting so whoops over here I have
two examples of visuals I've got a kind
of boring poor visual no offense to the
brand but it just looks a bit weird it
looks very aiish which is not what you
want to do obviously we're trying to
create visuals with AI but that's
there's a way to do it which I'll show
you in a second well later on in the
video but you see here it doesn't really
catch my eye um it's very all over the
place it's very
distracting whereas for this one it's
more of a scroll stepping one this is
actually a real photo it's not an AI one
but um you see it's very bold it's very
clean very modern um it really catches
my eye and it really does want to
communicate the Brand's um Vibe and
value very very clearly now the purpose
of a high confirm visual is to do one or
three or the following is to stop the
scroll is to help build a connection
with your customer customers it's helped
and it's there to help Drive
conversions um and ideally you want your
Vis to do all free especially when used
on ads um and the way you can do this um
is through using Color psychology so
basically just picking the right colors
to focus certain emotions which will
help to influence um how your customers
feel about your brand it needs to be eye
catch and of course you need to be bold
and unique um and stand out um
especially when you're running ads so
that it actually catches your customer
attention in a crowded field feed and
you're able to you know use strong
contrast is another way to do that as
well it has to be very clean and simple
um and have cognitive ease which is
basically a heris which um basically
means it basically allows your customers
to have a clear Focus um and this helps
to reduce decision fatigue people don't
want to be looking at your vision and
trying to like figure out what you're
trying to sell or why they should care
about your brand or your products so
make it as easy as possible for them to
understand your value and your product
as clearly as possible while still
looking good like in this example over
here there also needs to be brand
consistency so using the right colors
and styles and elements that are that
align with your brand and it's very
consistent across your different touch
points and this helps to build
familiarity and Trust um across your
brand over
time um using the right visuals to you
know tell a story about your brand and
your products and it just shows how your
you know need to show how your product
and brand fit into your customer Liv and
solve their problems and that can just
be done through yeah using the right
elements and props and settings Etc in
your visuals which will talk about more
later section and also just overall
building that emotional connection with
your customers and being able to evoke
an emotional response in them um your
dream customers and once you know your
dream customers in and out you'll able
to do this with ease and I'll show you
how to do that um shortly and this will
help you create a memorable impression
and help you to drive um action but yeah
that's I guess an overview of you know
why having visuals matter and how you
can start to create a high high
converting visuals um but moving on you
need to also know your brand identity
now your brand identity is basically the
heart and solve your brand and you need
to know this inside and out before
creating any visual in order to make
sure that it's effective and this will
be very foundational to everything
you're creating so if you don't know
your brand you know called values your
personality your Vibe your feeling
um anything basically that represents
your brand your visuals are just not
going to look and feel right they're
going to feel scattered they're going to
feel underline they're going to feel
very forgettable to dream
customers um and you need to know what
your brand stands for really really in
depth um and how you wanted to make a
customer feel in order to get them to
actually um you know buy from you which
is exactly what you want with your
visuals end of the day they're not just
there to look nice they're actually
there to kind of convert your customers
well convert C convert colde traffic
into you know paying
customers and it's just all about
communicating your Brand's message in a
way that resonates but yeah jumping in
there's three main areas of your brand
identity which you need to know in depth
um which will help with your creative
Direction so you need to know your core
values it's just basically what your
brand in a way stands for what are some
key words that your brand um wants to be
known for going to be known as you know
sustainable inclusive um is it for like
your community
transparent all authentic you know make
sure you actually know this for your
brand if you're not sure you know think
about your own values think about your
customer dream customer values and
incorporate that into your brand
identity but you should know this um
quite
clearly you also your brand objectives
um objectives sorry you know how would
people describe your brand to their
friends um and how would you also
describe your brand when I guess talking
to potential customers or pitching you
know are you bold are you playful are
you Sleek are you vibrant just really
understanding very clearly the the
objectives adjectives sorry what am I
saying objectives adjectives that um
represent your brand and just KN that
down and the dock and also what emotions
do you want your brand to feel um not
your brand to feel what emotions do you
want your customers to feel when
interacting with your brand do they want
to feel you know confident do they want
to feel Comfort excitement trust all of
that make sure you know that all down
and think about you know what's the
ideal emotions you want your customers
to feel in order to get get them to
convert and um purchase of you and
overall this will help to guide your
creative Direction um moving on as
mentioned about your customer you need
to understand them even more you know
because your visuals are made for them
they're not made for you you know when
you're making visuals you're not making
um something that you like to look of
obviously it's great if you do that but
you want to make sure that it actually
speaks to them um and actually make it
convert you need to know them deeply and
both the demographics and
psychographics now you want to also to
know you know what kind of visuals
colors Styles Etc going to grab their
attention and it resonate with them
emotionally um the better you understand
them the more your visuals will resonate
and more effective they will be for
driving results um so obviously we have
over here demographics which is you know
just the base level of um understanding
of your customers I guess is the
exterior whereas the um psych Graphics
is more of the Interior so the
psychology and how they think and how
they feel and how they look at life like
their values their interests their
lifestyle pain points challenges desires
all of that is really important if you
want to make visuals that you know
really resonate with them and also will
help you with your copy as well if you
you end up taking these visuals and you
know creating ads with
these and these are just some different
sources you can use to kind of
understand your customer a bit
more um so you can use chat gbt you can
use Shopify data whether that's your
reviews or customer data Reddit looking
at different posts or subreddits that
your customers are talking about your
products or your competitors or your
niche in general same as cor check
Amazon reviews Instagram comments
perplexity AI um it's like a research
Search tool highly recommend it if
you're trying to do
research um and also Tik Tok comments as
well and Tik Tok uh posts which are
related to your products or competitive
products or Niche um but yeah so I've
got a quick exercise that I highly
recommend if you're trying to even go in
more detail about your um Gene customers
it's called the day and life exercise
and this is where you get all your
research which you should have noted
down um a word
document um and you want to be able to
create a day in the life of your dream
customer and this will help you to
understand how your product fits into
the daily routine of your customers um
and how they need um and also their
needs and also is a very powerful way
for generating lifestyle visuals um for
your brand and I've got a prompt over
here if you really want this prompt um
send me a message I can send it over to
you um yeah s me message on if Instagram
Twitter LinkedIn whatever I'll put my
details in the
description but long story short it
basically just you know you you insert
your um Research into cck gbt and you
just talk about you know use the
information provided about your brand
and your customer I want you to create
for me a vivid detailed Narrative of the
day in the life of my dream
customer um the story should highlight
how product name fits into the daily
routine just the needs if it's their
pain points etc etc long story short
it's going to create you a long story
about how your product has um fits into
their Liv and I guess benefits them and
actually um you know um it can actually
help them improve their lifestyle and
help to fulfill both the
Practical um and inspirational desires
I've actually realized I've made some s
mistakes there but you get a Gest and
I'll just give you like a long narrative
basically that you can definitely get
some ideas from
um for the next stages but
yeah now you might have noticed we've
actually not talked about mid Journey at
all um so far in this video and that's
because you know you can't jump into mid
Journey just start to create you
actually need to know what you need to
create and why you're creating it and
the best way to do that is by actually
understanding your dream customers who
are the people you actually Crea the
visuals for you just don't know create
visuals for the sake of it you actually
want to make sure that it resonates um
so moving on to this stage is about
creating your mood board and this is
where you take all your research and you
visualize it and this will act as a
visual guide that will help you to I
guess gather inspiration inspiration and
visualize your creative Direction and
this should not only reflect your
product but the overall brand Vibe and
emotion you want your um vs to evoke so
I've got over here another chat gbt
prompt and what this is going to do it's
going to get your
research um about your brand identity
and your customer cust and it's going to
give you the most effective Search terms
and keywords that you can use on
platforms such as the ones below which
I'll get into in a second that will most
likely give you images that are aligned
with your brand aesthetic um in order to
fol the right emotion emotional response
in your customers in order to you know
create high converting visuals and again
if you want this chat GD prompt just
send me a message on my socials I'll
send that over to you but you can again
you can just pretty much screenshot if
you want doesn't matter happen to do
either but the different websites I use
for visual inspiration is Pinterest
which is just a I'm sure you know about
Pinterest just a uh image inspiration
website you can just save different
images you have over here just search
for what you want they've got a lot of
different images you can just kind of go
through different rabbit holes when you
click on the image you can just find
more and more and more da recommend
it um there's Instagram as well so just
by looking at your competitors
um uh I guess product photos or just
searching um in the search feature on
Instagram or through hashtags there's
also a website called Cosmos which is a
pretty cool um website kind of like
Pinterest that just kind of has some
very cool aesthetically pleasing unique
visuals which you know very very
definitely relevant for lifesty type
Brands like fashion uh Beauty skincare
all of that stuff definitely recommend
it you can search by color and search by
image as well um High recommend it it's
also Stills which is just um a proper
product photography stock image website
which is just high quality
professional um definitely get
inspiration from
here um be as well which is a creative
um inspirational website um but yeah
these five websites you can find
inspiration from you can find it from
anywhere really but these are just what
I
recommend but anyway when you're looking
for um insiration these are the
different components you want to look
out for so you want to look out for the
setting
in which the fures are you know I guess
shot in or take place in the shots the
lighting the colors the models
composition props camera angles textures
Etc look at all of these elements in
each photo you see and you just want to
make sure that you know at least for one
of these it of it resonates with your
customers and Alliance of your brand you
know you might see a product for example
if I just G Pinterest you might like for
example the colors used here you might
like the I don't know the shot you might
like the I guess the props the angles
you know find feel free to just find any
image over here that has something that
you like the look and feel of um that
comes across under these categories
either it could be either just one
category or all of them doesn't really
matter just sa anything that kind of
comes um under these areas cuz this is
going to help us going making a prompt
in mid Journey so once you've saved all
the images that you found on these
websit you then want to start organizing
them you can either do it on Pinterest
if you just found images on Pinterest
directly you could either do it using
millano which is a uh I guess a creative
organizational tool um we can create M
on there you can use canva you can use
anything really and you also use a tool
I use called k. a which I've used an
example of it here which I've created
for supplement brand that um I worked on
a project with and you can see over here
the images here are all consistent and
coherent they all kind of have the same
look feel and really really really
aligned the brand identity that um they
had outlined um you know they got the
same type of colors the same type of uh
I guess textures the same type of I
guess lighting short angles Etc and what
you want to do is when you're making
these move boards is that just put
anything down doesn't really matter cuz
you're going to ask yourself these four
questions so you're going to ask you
know does the image align with my
Brand's core identity and values know
what emotions does the image evoke and
Lin in my dream custom I'm messaging
does the image contribute to the overall
visual Direction and aesthetic of my
brand and is this image unique and
compet enough to stand for my
competitors now doesn't have to be yes
for all of these but it has to be at
least a three out of four I'd say
doesn't really matter you'll know
basically most cases it will be at least
free um this will just help you to
narrow the images and shots you like to
look and feel of that line best of your
brand and also don't be afraid to just
add an image you like the look of if
you're not 100% sure if you know your
customers might align with it if you
just like the look and feel of it cuz
it's your brand and you feel like it
aligns with your brand feel fre just add
it in day you know end of the day it is
your brand um and adding your own
creative flare to it um will you know
help a lot um so yeah that's it for mood
boarding and now we can jump into mid
Journey which is the part I'm sure you
guys have been waiting for now if you
don't know what mid journey is mid
journey is an AI generation toour it's
kind of like chat DBT but for images um
whereby you can of you know give it a
text prompt and you it space out an
image um the beauty of big journey is
that it's very powerful you can pretty
much create anything with it but it all
comes down to the right prompting now a
prompting technique I like to use and
was inspired by is called asset hacking
and this was kind of coined or I guess
discovered if that's the right word to
say by someone called Rory Flynn sh out
Rory um he's quite big in the mid
Journey AI image space he's got his own
po he has his own course and um he's
done a couple talks that you can find on
YouTube that really talks about this um
concept um so if you want to learn more
about mid journey and more about this
feel free to just check out his videos
um highly recommend it and I think one
thing I want to talk about is the term
good artist copy and great artist still
now basically this aligns to this
because what you're going to be doing in
this stage is is called You're basically
going to be reverse engineering image
and creating variations of it based on
your brand you know you're going to get
an initial image and then you're going
to use AI to break it down and build it
up in a way that's aligned with your
brand and this is going to be very very
powerful and generating you know lots of
related images for your brand and it
will save a lot of time and effort
compared to just creating your prompt
from scratch and this will just make
sure that the image you create aren't
too similar with the you know initial
image if that makes sense now I've got
an example over here of a skincare
product that I found on Pinterest um and
what I'm going to do is use a mid
Journey gbt bot which I've created
um over
here um which if you want me to send
this over to you send me a message I'll
happy to send you over the one I've made
um but long story short it takes this
prompt um structure so photography
Styles subjects supp and objects
background colors lighting camera
details Etc um and this helps to then
create a uh prompt image prompt for Mid
Journey which basically just breaks down
this image into text for format in a way
in which a a all that Ma can understand
in a way that is in the eyes of a
photographer cuz when you're creating
product photography product visuals you
want to talk to Mid Journey as if you're
trying to do your own photo shoot rather
than just telling it for example create
me a oh sorry imagine a skare jar on a
green Mossy platform that's not going to
be enough to create you a high quality
visual so by doing this it makes sure
that you create you know fa realistic
product photography and from there we're
able to create this as you see it's not
100% close to it but it gets a pretty
good result and a good starting point
now let's say you have a drinks brand um
and you want to now add your drink to
the scene you need to just then change
the subject which was
this into your drink can and you just
need to just describe your product as
simple as
possible um because in the latest stages
we're actually going to add your product
into it but we'll get into that we just
want to describe your product um as
simple as possible and add it into the
subject and by doing that we're able to
create this also one thing to know once
if you change for example skincare jar
to a can you want to make sure that it
doesn't get you don't for example leave
any
um mention of the previous subject in
the new prompt you make for example
let's say I just changed that and I kept
this in then the jav still appears just
make sure you clean up the prompt and
actually make an effort to make sure
that it all makes sense still so yeah
overall you see this you get this um
drink can once you've changed the prompt
and if you want to then change something
else in it for example the surface which
was the mobile peddle store from the
mossy one you get this and it looks
quite different but you've now got a
starting point to start to kind of
create your own you know product photos
and product visuals that actually make
sense to your
Brands um just gives you a good sign
point you can see it looks quite real
STI and it gives you yeah way better um
quality of images compared to you know
um just putting a drink can on a marble
pedestal that makes sense
great um so now if you want to start to
build on your prompts in your images
another thing I like to use is style
references and this is basically when
use an image as a style reference in
your prompt influence the style and
aesthetic of your image you want to make
a mid journey and this really just
focuses on the colors the composition
and the overall style of your images and
this will be very powerful when you want
to make your own I guess consistent
visual aesthetic for your brand let's
say you have an image um that you've
used or a product photo that you have of
your in your brand um you could then use
that um image journey to reference it
for example I'll jump to my journey now
and for example you can just upload the
image over here um I just got some
random images here for a mood Bo I was
creating but basically long story is
short you just you know click on that
and then you can just for example I'm
just going to get an example I'm going
get this prompt and just do
it if I just copy that and then paste
that there and then click on this
paperclip
here and then
enter it's going to basically reference
the colors um and the overall style um
of this image and then you know make it
influence this prompt which you'll see
in a second
I take a bit of
time but you see it does start to
influence it a bit obviously it's not
perfect but it's something that you need
to play around with um and the thing
with star references is that you can
also add a weight to it and the weight
just tells you how much to reference the
image style um for the final image um
you can see over here to do that you
need to add this parameter to the end of
The Prompt for example we'll do that
again you just do D- s SW which is style
weight um and you put a number in which
you want the weight to be the higher the
number the stronger it's going to
influence be influenced by the image I
you see over here in these the examples
the default is
100 um but the max is a th000 and it
just depends on how strong you want it
to be it really just depends on the
image that you're referencing and the
overall prompt that you have you have to
just play around of it um but yeah
that's just that's just what you that's
what you should just do if you want to
start to you know create images which
going to reflect a certain sty aesthetic
and it helps you to then start to build
up very consistent uh visual assets for
your brand now another way to do that is
through using mid Journey's mood War
feature um and this is basically instead
of just picking one image to reference
like' done over here it you can
reference as as many phots as possible
um to be to inspire you to create a
certain mood of V for your brand and
it's going to be like a a vision board
for ideas you want to capture now you
want to make sure that when you're doing
this the prompts you use are a lot
lighter they're not as intense as this
one you just have to cut it down just
put the more the most core components
such as the subject the product
photography type the setting all of that
you don't have to probably talk about
colors as much or lighting or
compositions um and you see over here
when I've done it for this prompt it's
giv me um these outputs which you know
obviously aren't all purple but you can
kind of see where the St and five is
kind of being fed into here so this is
very powerful if you have done the mve
boarding stage which you know I hope
you've done it in depth because what you
can do is go to your mood board pick
images which are um the same in I guess
theme and mood and style upload it into
here and in the mid Journey you are able
to then use that um to actually create
visuals which are consistent with your
brand aesthetic and that just saves you
a lot of time comparing to just getting
trying to get the prompts right or using
one image for the style reference
obviously this has a time and place for
it but um this know requires a lot of
experimentation um and this is something
that you you know want me to make a
video on I'm happy to do that to go a
bit deeper into how i' use this for you
know projects with my
clients um but yeah and finally is the
case parameter which I like to use and
for this it's just basically influences
how VAR initial grids you U make a mid
Journey um come out like so for example
a higher K will produce more unusual
unexpected results and competions whilst
a lower one will give you more reliable
and repeatable results so for
example if I do a chaos of let's say
50 you see over here there's no chaos
and it's all pretty similar quite
consistent if I add a chaos of 50 it's
going to make sure that each tile is
very very different um and I'll I'll
explain why this is really powerful when
creating images of my
journey now you see over here this image
that image that image and that image are
completely different and what I like
about this Fe this um parameter and why
I think it's powerful is because let's
say you're not too sure which direction
to go towards for your brand but you
know what type of colors what type of
mood what type of feeling you want it
will keep that pretty consistent but it
will kind of put it in you'll kind of
give it a bit of a
different I don't know a different Edge
I guess and what you can do is just keep
on running it and just find a direction
you like to look of for example let's
say you like this and then you can just
kind of you know vary it can VAR it
strong and it give you even more
creative direction towards that um
um where is it
sorry that will load in a
second but yeah you're able to then go
down Rabbit Hole creating images which
all look the same pretty
much um and yeah that's the beauty of
mid journey is that you can just kind of
like go for rabbit holes try different
stuff try different parameters try
different prompting structures and just
start to create different um czy ideas
and by starting off with asset hacking
it just gives you that great starting
point that you wouldn't have had before
whereby you know you're just looking at
your mid Journey screen and not knowing
what to imagine you probably have an
image in your head of what you like to
have but just by breaking it down taking
the initial image you have that you've
gotten from your mood board breaking it
down um by this you're able to then get
a structure which you can then build
upon it's also important to just not you
know get this image do do that and then
just use that like definitely don't do
that make sure you add your own twist to
things do not copy steal it's completely
different I can I you definitely need to
just be adding your own um source to it
do not be stealing people's work you
don't want to get trouble for that for
that so um yeah that's pretty much it
for asset hacking um some M Journey tips
to give you you want to make sure you're
using strong descriptive words um just
to give mid Journey a lot to work with
and actually point it in the right
direction you want to then also focus on
one main product or subject in your
photo so it doesn't get too confused
start with that and then kind of add on
another product if you want to I just
highly recommend starting with one main
product in your product visuals you also
want to use you know photography
terminology because you know when you're
creating photo realistic uh product
visuals you need to speak to M Journey
as if it's like a photographer and
you're the creative director you need to
just direct it um in a way that actually
is relevant to what you're trying to
make rather than just being like as I
said before a skare jar on a green Mossy
um platform if you need to learn more
about photography terminology just go
and chat gbt and be like what's the word
um what's the terminology for a low
angle if that's not the right
terminology for it um and yeah just go
through the rabbit hole also feel free
to use this chat gbt prom maker sorry
mid Journey PR maker that um I have um
have have to send that over to you guys
if you want just send me a message as
mentioned
before um also make sure using the same
camera angles light and the composition
for consistent style um of course your
visuals to make sure that you know
everything it stays coherent also check
out the explore page for inspiration um
just go here and explore you're able to
just find different
images um you like to look off you can
also search let's say you want to do it
for a drink can product photo
you find some cool ideas some of these
are just quite plain to be fair but
let's say you want to get inspired by
that obviously the prompt isn't the best
but you kind of know what I'm talking
about you can just kind of go in here
and just kind of find image you like see
what prompts they use and just break it
down kind of like how you're doing with
a hacking pretty much and the most
important thing is just experiment and
have fun with my journey there's no
right or wrong way to really use my
journey what you're just doing is just
kind of playing around trying different
prompts trying different parameters like
we've done over here and seeing what
sticks and what works you know some of
the best things I've made in my journey
are just things that I've just done
randomly and just had fun with and it's
just come out um unexpectedly and it's
actually gotten results so have to give
yourself time and the freedom to just
create what you want don't be pressuring
yourself um end of the day we're going
to end up polishing up the visuals that
we've generated in the journey in
Photoshop which I'll go into now so this
is the part most people really skip out
on when it comes to you know
making I guess product photography and
product visuals on my journey is that
you know they may just generate scenes
like this and then stop there and not
really know what to do with it and this
is where Photoshop comes in m j is a
great starting point to kind of come up
with Concepts and kind of come up with
scenes that really look you know unique
and vially appealing and you can just
generate with ease for your dream
customers and which are aligned with
your brand but first is where the real
magic happens
with Photoshop you're able to you know
add the product your product sorry into
the scenes for example these are some
products um I've generated in my journey
and this are just the before this is how
it looked like before I went on photos
shop so it was like that for this one
that for that one that for that one that
for that one and all I just did was get
a product
render for all of these and add it to
the scene and then just use some
photoshop skills to add some depth to it
by you know Shadows lighting
highlights you know color grading color
matching all of that to make sure that
it all ties in so that it doesn't even
look like this was generated um using
mid Journey you know it you see how this
all looks like it it fits into the scene
as if I made this image journey well
that's because I just made sure that the
product Rend I added into the scene
Blends in to the generated scene so that
you know instead of it being like Oh
it's AI blah blah it's just that AI
assisted me in making making these
visuals which is pretty powerful and I
feel this is the best way to use mid
Journey you know people talk about how
you know people quite skeptical with
about AI art and mid journey and people
think it's poor quality and that's
because people aren't adding a human
touch to it I feel like with AI tools
you know the inputs are first of all the
most important thing which we've pretty
much um where which are pretty much
which we pretty much sorry that got lost
which we pretty much done in the other
stages the inputs um through the
research and also through like the asset
hacking etc
etc but
um the be the part that comes after is
the human touch so it's having good
inputs entering it into mid journey and
then the output poing it up with human
touch and creativity to create these
high quality product visuals now if you
don't have a product render or image
it's highly important that you have one
um three ways you can do that is through
hiring a 3D renderer to model your
product render for you you can probably
find one on five upwork you can also
send your product to a photographer to
just take a photo couple photos of your
product on a plain white background or
just buy a light box on Amazon and doing
it yourself and just taking it from your
iPhone doesn't really matter just make
sure the photos are of good quality and
the renders of good quality cuz um you
know once you've paid for that and once
you've got that you can just use this
for multiple scenes as you as you see so
um just a onetime I guess investment
that will definitely pay off but I'm
sure you you should have you know surely
you should have a part of rental image
for your brand if not definitely worth
investing in a high quality render or
product image um these are just the
steps and checks that I do when making
um my images in Photoshop which I'll go
into in a second but what I do basically
is that I remove the placeholder image
so in this case is the this over here
and then I add the product into the
scene I then match the color of the
product and the scene so that it hits in
cohesively I add the liting the shadow
to the product to add a bit of depth I
also add any contact Shadow that's
necessary add any highlights to match
the light source which is done over here
I app the background to add some depth
of field to then have more focus on the
product um and the subject in this case
the hand and the sweet package I then
add some noise to add some texture to
the product i f the edges to make sure
it Blends into the
scene you can also add light effects
such as lens flare Spotlight effects and
light beams to kind of make it just seem
a bit more you know polished up this
also a color gradient to kind of a Vera
certain mood for example if you have a I
guess a
luxury like sleep wear brand you might
use warm colors to kind of evoke comfort
and you know
warmth um and also yeah just add in some
sharpness and Clarity where necessary
and then yeah adding just the final
touches to the contrast highlight
shadows and color balance um in the
global
adjustments so jumping on to photoshop
right now I'm just going to show you the
different layers I have um just going to
close all this just to show you exactly
how my process looks like and how
everything kind of ties
together um so I'm I'm just going to
hide all these
layers and just show you how it started
off with so I start off with this and
I'll just show you if I can actually
remember the order I did it in how I
built this so I added a product
in um and I used neural Fe NE neural
filters my bad to match the color into
the
scene um and then I started to add you
know some
Shadows uh some ligh in and then
highlights and I've added some more
shadows and some more
Shadows um and then I've added the hand
on top of it so that it's actually
looking like it's grabbing it and I've
added some Shadows on the finger over
there I've then what have I done I've
added changed that to be red to keep it
consistent with The Branding and the
colors I've added a fish to make it a
bit more playful and fun cuz it's a fun
brand and I've added some noise um to
the overall scene so this one didn't
have many layers but you can see here
you know it's pretty quick to do it's
just about having an eye for it you know
it's a lot easier to then you know do
this as in take the product render and
add it to the scene compared to you
actually having to build the entire
scene for example you having to get a
hand model and put it in there you
having to find a background you having
to do all these things all you need to
do is just add a product render to the
scene and that's it the other stuff has
been done on Mid Journey um it's just
all about you just adding the product
into the scene and that's it and there's
a lot tutorials out there to learn how
to do this and I'll probably be making
one shortly um in the coming weeks to
show you guys my entire Photoshop work
flowing process that you can kind of
follow to kind of start to do this
yourself because I know Photoshop can be
quite you know overwhelming but you know
if you're just adding a product into a
scene and you know you know what you're
doing and you follow these checkpoints I
can't see why you can't pick this up
quickly and start to make these H offals
in what half an hour on Photoshop um if
you want any recommendations you know
picks and perfect on YouTube highly
recommend them if you want to learn
about Photoshop and compos sighting
composting is just basically the art of
you know adding different uh I guess
images into one image and making it all
fit
in
um but yeah that is pretty much it I
hope that was helpful um if you're an
Ecom brand um who is interested in
having visuals like these and can't you
know be bothered to follow this process
uh um I actually help Brands you know
create visuals for their brand um for
their you know email marketing ads
product page etc etc so this that
something that you would be interested
in um feel free to pick a call down
below um my plan is to start to you know
upload more videos maybe on a weekly
basis to talk about more about these
steps in more detail you know um just to
give you guys a bit more value to show
you that how you can actually start
using your journey in your workflow and
in your business cuz I really feel like
you know in 2025 brand not using M
Journey are really missing out um it
just gives you so much you know
potential to actually just scale your
brand and kind of create these cool
unique Aesthetics and experiences for
your customers and just make you stand
out so yeah it's definitely worth it if
you're not if you were hesitant before
then I hope you're you don't buying into
it now but yeah that's pretty much it
and yeah if you want any of the activity
prompts I've used any the resources I've
used feele to send me a message on
Instagram or LinkedIn or Twitter and
I'll send that over to you but yeah
peace